# Keen Wilson

keencwilson@gmail.com | (913) 242-2528 | Olympia, WA 98501

Github: github.com/keenwilson | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/keenwilson | Portfolio: https://keenwilson.github.io

### **SUMMARY**

Keen has full-stack programming experience designing, writing, and deploying rich web applications with test coverage on a weekly sprints CI/CD DevOps basis. She architects and engineers front-end user interface (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Typescript, Redux) with accessibility standards (WCAG, ADA), back-end APIs (NodeJs, Python), and database relationships and modeling (SQL, NoSQL, ORM). Keen also works with cloud technologies (AWS), configuration management (Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform), automated testing, and CI/CD (Bazel, CodePipeline, GitLab).

Keen enjoys working with the entire application stack, collaborating with market-oriented teams to build user-focused applications, solving complicated problems, and delivering clean, functional, well-documented software in a highly collaborative, remote-friendly environment.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Optimally** / Software Engineer (Remote-First)

July 2020 - Nov 2021, Leawood, Kansas

An expense reduction technology platform that helps businesses save money on operating expenses

- Prototyped, built, tested, and debugged Optimally's responsive progressive-enhanced data-driven scalable front-end applications (HTML, CSS/LESS, JavaScript, React, React Hooks, React Testing Library)
- Configured CORS support for private Kubernetes services to communicate with AWS API Gateway
- Architected, developed, and tested object-oriented REST APIs (Python)
- Defined access pattern and optimized pagination query to NoSQL database service (AWS DynamoDB)
- Wrote, planned, and applied infrastructure as code using declarative configuration files (Terraform)
- Formulated attribute-based access control (ABAC) to ensure platform security
- Automated build and test optimization (Bazel); implemented DevOps techniques and processes to improve platform quality, cost-effectiveness, and product feedback loop

### Finsignum / Software Engineer

February 2019 - July 2020, Prairie Village, Kansas

Healthcare financial budgeting and forecasting consulting

- Developed and tested consulting visualization dashboards (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, state management)
- Built and refactored a private Python library that contains standard data analysis code (Python Pandas, SQL)
- Wrote automated testing in JavaScript (Jest, Enzyme) and Python (unittest, Pandas DataFrame)
- Architected and deployed event-driven data processing microservices on AWS with the serverless framework
- Configured processing queues, application integrations, and low-latency user feedback (AWS SES, SNS, SQS)
- Monitored and traced application performance (Sentry, AWS CloudWatch)
- Documented weekly changelog to convey noteworthy changes to stakeholders

## Sabbatical / Freelance Web Developer

June 2016 - February 2019, Kansas City, Missouri

Three-year sabbatical to raise two small children in three different cities around the world, i.e., Bangkok, New York City, and Kansas City

- Created static marketing websites with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Volunteered as a mentor to help beginners learn how to build web applications at Coding & Cocktails, introductory coding series organized by Kansas City Women in Technology

**Wunderman Thompson (formerly JWT Bangkok) / Account Manager** October 2015 - June 2016, Bangkok, Thailand Part of the WPP Group, one of the world's largest communications corporations.

• Managed cross-functional teams on projects which created promotional materials for consumer goods clients across Southeast Asia, and was involved in Social Media Marketing, and Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

### **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina Kenan-Flagler Business School / MBA University of Kansas / Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Chulalongkorn University / BA in Communication Arts (GPA 3.65)

Chapel Hill, North Carolina Overland Park, Kansas Bangkok, Thailand